# Navin Durai S M

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India



smnavin65@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/smnavindurai

## Summary

Hi, I am Navin Durai:

I am undergoing my bachelors degree in Chennai. With hands-on experience in multiple programming languages I have done mini projects in Spring Boot, React, Node, Flutter, Django, NextJS and many more.

FRONT-END: React JS, Next JS, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

BACKEND: Spring Boot (Microservices), Node JS, Django, Express JS

DATABASE: Postgresql, Mysql, MongoDB

Miscellaneous: Flutter, IOT

Github: https://github.com/Navin3d

### **Experience**



### **Software Engineering Trainee**

NatWest Group Sep 2022 - Present (4 months)

## **Java Software Developer**

NatWest Group Mar 2022 - Sep 2022 (7 months)

## Full Stack Developer

Brainlox

Sep 2021 - Nov 2021 (3 months)

## Java Software Developer

Saloop.official Sep 2021 - Nov 2021 (3 months)

# **%** Digital Marketing Intern

**OnePercent** Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 (2 months)

#### **Education**

Panimalar Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Science Nov 2020 - Jun 2024

Anitha Kumaran Matric hr secondary School

High School Diploma, Computer Science 2018 - 2020

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Introduction to Programming Using Python HackerRank D2C579DA2537
- Introduction to Programming Using Java HackerRank 4A49DC45C9E6
- Rest API (Intermediate) Certificate HackerRank E6CB7CBE8719
- **Event Driven Microservices Spring Boot Kafka and Elastic** Udemy UC-fc3f8e93-92e9-42ba-9c66-14050842fe48
- Become a Front End Web Developer JavaScript for Beginners Udemy UC-229fe550-16d5-4e34-875b-d6acb0b9ab0a
- **Create and Manage Cloud Resources** Google 1951102
- Google Cloud Essentials Google 1950655
- **C** Kubernetes in Google Cloud Google 2041444
- **C** Deploy to Kubernetes in Google Cloud Google 2044875
- **DevOps Essentials** Google 2047992

- **G** Intermediate ML: TensorFlow on Google Cloud Google 2418394
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) Udemy UC-13a35865-818b-404c-9932-a31e80d69ce5
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) Udemy UC-13a35865-818b-404c-9932-a31e80d69ce5
- Computer Vision with OpenCV and Deep Learning Udemy UC-4dd93dde-c731-4ba2-b82c-9a96d2f349b5

### **Skills**

Python (Programming Language) • J2EE Web Services • JavaServer Pages (JSP) • Django REST Framework • Next.js • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Spring Boot • React.js • Flutter • Django

#### **Honors & Awards**

- TOYCATHON 2021 finalist Government of India
  Mar 2021
- Smart India Hackathon 2022 Winner Government Of India
  Jul 2022